the function e to the X is a very
important very famous function within
mathematics and indeed it has this
interesting property which is that the
derivative of e to the X is just the
same function that is if I take a point
like how about 1 here all right
so 1 e to the 1 is going to have the
value just e to the 1 is e and so if I
figure out what the slope is that the
height of this which looks like a little
bit over 2 that's basically the value of
e here is the same thing as the slope of
this particular function they have the
same function value and slope and indeed
if I take in my slope down here or my
slope up here it doesn't really matter
it's always gonna have the same slope as
a function value indeed you could ask a
broader category like there's all these
different exponents like 2 to the X and
3 to the X and PI to the X and 100 to
the X e to the X is defined to be or one
way you can define it to be is defined
to be the number such that the
derivative of e to the X is itself we
define e to be the number where this
property is true so we really are gonna
like Exponential's as we go forward in
our course and they have this really
nice property indeed what you can do is
take the derivative of the derivative of
e to the X first wrote it takes UVs
second river takes you to the X you take
a hundred rooms in a row you get back to
e to the X and so forth so where are we
at we now know how to take the
derivatives of two different types of
functions the derivatives of an
exponential like e to the X and the
derivative of a power like X to the n so
we've got those sort of two like
baseline kind of functions and then the
additive 'ti in the scalar
multiplication those are ways that I can
combine them so for example I could have
a polynomial which is a bunch of power
rules or I can have like e to the X plus
x squared and I would be able to combine
them by these different rules so I
haven't got all functions by any means
but we're developing so far a decent
list